Guide to the Ernest Nagel Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Ernest Nagel Papers,
1930-1988
Nagel, Ernest, 1901-
15 linear ft. (ca. 5,100 items in 35 Boxes).
Columbia University Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Butler Library, New York, NY 10027.
4078453
Biographical Note
Ernest Nagel (1901-1985), philosopher and University Professor Emeritus at Columbia University. Nagel received a B.S. (1923) from City College, and a M.A. (1925) and Ph.D. (1930) from Columbia. First appointed to Columbia's faculty in 1930, Nagel became John Dewey Professor of Philosophy in 1955 and University Professor in 1967.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, manuscripts, speeches, notebooks, notes, teaching materials, subject files, clippings, printed materials and books of Ernest Nagel. Included among the correspondence are William J. Bennett, Rudolph Carnap, Kurt Gödel, Adolph Grünbaum, C. G. Hemple, Paul Lazarsfeld, William J. McGill and Morton White. The collection's manuscripts include most of Nagel's essays and articles as well as drafts of his major works, including "The Structure of Science" (1961). The teaching materials contain syllabi, reading lists and lecture plans from the philosophy courses Nagel taught at Columbia. The collection also includes numerous manuscripts and printed materials by other authors which were inscribed to Nagel. In addition, there are printed materials and printed books by Nagel at the end of the collection.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 11 series:
Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
Series II: Arranged Correspondence
Series III: Arranged Manuscripts
Series IV: Speeches and Lectures
Series V: Notebooks
Series VI: Notes
Series VII: Teaching Materials
Series VIII: Subject Files
Series IX: Manuscripts inscribed to E. Nagel
Series X: Printed Materials
Series XI: 1989 Addition
Subjects
Gödel, Kurt.; Hempel, Carl G. (Carl Gustav), 1905-1997.; Hook, Sidney, 1902-1989.; Lazarsfeld, Paul Felix.; McGill, William J. (William James), 1922-; White, Morton Gabriel, 1917-; Philosophy, Modern--20th century.; Philosophers
Access Restrictions
The following boxes are located off-site: 2-37. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
07/25/88 M-88-07-25 Nagel, Ernest, 1980; Alexander and Sidney Nagel, 1988 Gift
Gift of Ernest Nagel, 1980; Alexander and Sidney Nagel, 1988.
- Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
  - Hook, Sidney (Box 1)
  - Santayana, George (Box 1)
  - Shi, Hu (Box 1)
- Series II: Arranged Correspondence
  - A - J (Box 1)
  - K - W (Box 1)
  - Bailey, Herbert S., Jr. (Box 1)
  - Bennett, William J. (Box 1)
  - Bentley, Arthur (Box 1)
  - Berenda, Carlton W. (Box 1)
  - Berkson, Joseph (Box 1)
  - Black, Max (Box 1)
  - Brandt, Richard (Box 1)
  - Bryson, Lyman (Box 1)
  - Carnap, Rudolf (Box 1)
  - Chroust, Anton-Hermann (Box 1)
  - Church, Alonzo (Box 1)
  - Cumming, Robert D. (Box 1)
  - Feigl, Herbert (Box 1)
  - Fraenkel, George K. (Box 1)
  - The Free Press (Box 1)
  - Gödel, Kurt (Box 1)
  - Grünbaum, Adolf (Box 1)
  - Harcourt, Brace and World, (1) - (2) ) (Box 1)
  - Hempel, C. G. ("Pete") (Box 1)
  - International Institute for the Unity of Science (Box 1)
  - Janus Books (Box 1)
  - Katz, Leo (Box 1)
  - Kolakowski, Leszek (Box 1)
  - Laudan, Larry (Box 1)
  - Lazarsfeld, Paul (Box 1)
  - McGill, William J. (Box 1)
  - Morgenbesser, Sidney (Box 1)
  - Nagel, Ernest, ( (carbons, etc.) (Box 1)
  - New York University Press (Box 1)
  - Parsons, Charles D. (Box 1)
  - Phi Delta Kappa Society (Box 1)
  - Purdom, Paul (Box 1)
  - Reichenbach, Hans. (Box 1)
  - Sovern, Michael (Box 1)
  - Toulmin, Stephen (Box 1)
  - White, Morton (Box 1)
  - Zeisel, Hans (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (1) - (3) (Box 2)
- Series III: Arranged Manuscripts
  - America Illustrated statement (Box 2)
  - Assumptions in Economic Theory (Box 2)
  - [Biographical portraits of philosophers] (Box 2)
  - Biology [incomplete] (Box 2)
  - Max Black (Encyclopedia of Philosophy) (Box 2)
  - G. Spencer Brown Probability and Scientific Inference., ( Review) (Box 2)
  - A Budget of Problems in the Philosophy of Science (Box 2)
  - [Business school seminar] (Box 2)
  - Butler Gold Medal Speech, 1980 (Box 2)
  - Carnap's Theory of Induction (1) - (3) (Box 2)
  - Causal Inferences in the Social Sciences (Box 2)
  - Certainty in Natural Science (Box 2)
  - Changing Conceptions of Science (Box 2)
  - Charles Peirce's Place in Philosophy (Box 2)
  - The Cognitive Status of Theories (Box 2)
  - Cohen Week Celebration Speech (Box 2)
  - Columbia College Award Speech (Box 2)
  - Comments on John Dewey, Logic (Box 2)
  - Comment on Fuller, Human Purposes and Natural Law (Box 2)
  - Comments on Papers by Dr. Crombie and Father Clark (Box 2)
  - [Comments on Professor Holton] (Box 2)
  - [Comments on Professor Toulmin] (Box 2)
  - The Competence of Reason (Box 2)
  - Conference on Scientific Spirit (Box 2)
  - Creativity in Science (Box 2)
  - Current Critiques of Science as a Cumulative Enterprise (Box 2)
  - D'Amato on Law and Custom (Box 2)
  - The Debt We Owe to G. E. Moore (Box 2)
  - Definition and Specification of Meaning (Box 2)
  - Determinism and Development (Box 2)
  - Dewey Lecture, Brandeis, 1959 (Box 3)
  - Dewey's Lectures on Ethical Theory (Box 3)
  - Dewey's Lectures on Logic (Box 3)
  - Dewey's Logic of Inquiry (Box 3)
  - Differentiation and Unification in the Natural Sciences (Box 3)
  - Dispositional Concepts (Box 3)
  - Do Life Processes Transcend Physics and Chemistry? (Box 3)
  - Eighth International Congress of Philosophy. Address (Box 3)
  - Encyclopedia Americana, 1954 (Box 3)
  - Encyclopedia Americana, 1958 (Box 3)
  - The Enforcement of Morals (Box 3)
  - Evidence as Justification (Box 3)
  - Experience and Probability., (1st Draft.; 2nd Draft; 3rd Draft; 4th Draft; 5th Draft; 6th Draft; Final Draft (1) - (2) (Box 3)
  - Explanation and Structure of Scientific Knowledge (Box 3)
  - Fact, Value and Human Purpose (Box 3)
  - Fair Play and Civil Disobedience (Box 3)
  - The Formation of Modern Concepts of Formal Logic in the Development of Geometry (1) - (4) (Box 3)
  - Freedom and Authority in Scientific Method (Box 4)
  - Freedom and Civilization [Sakharov Conference] (Box 4)
  - A Frequency Theory of Probability (1) - (3) (Box 4)
  - Functionalism in the Social Sciences (Box 4)
  - Gšdel's Proof. 1st Draft.; 2nd Draft.; 3rd Draft.; 4th Draft.; 5th Draft.; 6th Draft. (1) - (2); 7th Draft.; 7th Draft. Revisions.; Final Draft (Box 4)
  - Ernest H. Hutten Language of Modern Physics., ( Review) (Box 4)
  - Impossible Numbers -- A Chapter in the History of Modern Logic (Box 4)
  - Impressions of European Universities: The Nineteen-Thirties (Box 4)
  - [Indefiniteness] (Box 4)
  - Introduction to R. Condon, Probability. (Box 4)
  - Introduction to A. DeMorgan, Budget. (Box 4)
  - Introduction to Greenberg and Gershenson, Anaxagoras. (Box 4)
  - Introduction to A. GrŸnbaum (Box 4)
  - Introduction to Logic and Scientific Method., ( 1st Draft. (1) - (3) (Box 4)
  - Introduction to Logic and Scientific Method, ( 2nd Draft. (1) - (6); 3rd Draft.) (Box 5)
  - Introduction to J. S. Mill, Philosophy of Scientific Method. (Box 5)
  - Introduction to Watson, Understanding Physics. (Box 5)
  - Is Biology Different from Physics? (Box 5)
  - Is the Laplacian Theory of Probability Tenable? (Box 5)
  - Arnold Isenberg Tribute (Box 5)
  - Issues in the Logic of Reductive Explanations. (Box 5)
  - William James (Box 5)
  - Journal of the History of Biology. Comment. (Box 5)
  - The Judgment of Practise. (Box 5)
  - Krikorian Party Comments (Box 5)
  - Liberalism and Intelligence. (Box 5)
  - A Limitation of the Axiomatic Method. (Box 5)
  - Logic Without Metaphysics. Introduction. (Box 5)
  - Logical Empiricism -- Its Achievements and Its Promise. (Box 5)
  - Logical Positivism and A Priori Knowledge. (Box 5)
  - Logical vs. Psychological Problems of Induction. (Box 5)
  - Man's Right to Know and Free Use Thereof. (Box 5)
  - Mathematics: An Indispensable Tool of Physical Inquiry, ( Review) (Box 5)
  - Mathematics: The Nature of Mathematics, ( television program) (Box 5)
  - Mathematics: Paradoxes, ( television program) (Box 5)
  - Meaning and Knowledge. (1) - (2) (Box 6)
  - The Meaning of Probability. (Box 6)
  - Memorandum on Philosophy in Relation to the Sciences. (Box 6)
  - Method in Social and Natural Science. (Box 6)
  - Methodological Issues in Psychoanalytic Theory. (Box 6)
  - The Methods of Science. (Box 6)
  - Mill's Logic. (Box 6)
  - Mr. Wheelwright's Wisdom. (Box 6)
  - National Teach-In, Washington D.C. Address. (Box 6)
  - The Nature and Aim of Science. (Box 6)
  - Nature and Convention. (Box 6)
  - Nature, Man and Science. (Box 6)
  - The Nature of Scientific Explanation. (Box 6)
  - On the Origin of Dialectic and Syllogism in Greek Philosophy. (Box 6)
  - On the Interpretation of Probability Calculi. (Box 6)
  - On the Logic of Measurement. Chapter 3; Chapter 7. (Box 6)
  - On the Method of Verstehen as the Sole Method of Philosophy. (Box 6)
  - On Three Arguments in Support of Natural Law. (Box 6)
  - [Oral History Interview Transcript] (Box 6)
  - Peirce Review. (Box 6)
  - The Philosopher Looks at Science. (Box 6)
  - Philosophical Concepts of Atheism. (Box 6)
  - Philosophical Interpretations of Contemporary Biology. (Box 6)
  - Philosophical Problems in Biology. (Box 6)
  - Philosophy in Educational Research. (Box 6)
  - The Philosophy of Science. (Box 7)
  - The Philosophy of Science, May 1932 (Box 7)
    [Radio Lecture]
  - The Philosophy of Science, University of Delaware, 1961 (Box 7)
  - Philosophy of Science and Philosophy of Education. (Box 7)
  - Philosophy of Science -- Assessment of Evidence. (Box 7)
  - The Place of Science in a Liberal Education. (Box 7)
  - Predictability and Scientific Knowledge. (Box 7)
  - Preference, Evaluation and Reflective Choice. (Box 7)
  - Princeton Conference, 5 Nov. 1965 (Box 7)
  - Probability (Logic). (Box 7)
  - Probability and Non-Demonstrative Inference. (Box 7)
  - The Problem of Induction. (Box 7)
  - The Quest for Uncertainty. (Box 7)
  - Rationality in Judicial Decisions. (Box 7)
  - Reduction and Autonomy of the Sciences. (Box 7)
  - Reductive Explanations and Scientific Revolutions. (Box 7)
  - A Rejoinder to Putnam. (Box 7)
  - The Relation Between the Social and the Natural Sciences. (Box 7)
  - The Relation of Sign to Object Signified. (Box 7)
  - Relativism and the Problems of a Working Historian. (Box 7)
  - Relativity and Twentieth-Century Intellectual Life. (Box 7)
  - Reply to "An Objective Probabilism." (Box 7)
  - The Rise of Modern Science. (Box 7)
  - Rorty Talk. Comments, Spring 1973 (Box 7)
  - Science and Culture, Bard College (Box 7)
  - Science and Culture (Box 7)
    [Phi Beta Kappa Society]
  - Science and Knowledge, ( 1st Draft and Notes (1) - (2); 2nd Draft.; Final Draft.) (Box 7)
  - [Science and Mechanics] (1) - (2) (Box 8)
  - Science and Semantic Realism. (Box 8)
  - Science and the Humanities. (Box 8)
  - Science as a Way of Life. (Box 8)
  - Scientific American, ( Reviews) (Box 8)
  - Scientific Laws and Theories. (Box 8)
  - The Scientific Man. (Box 8)
  - The Scientific Method, Jan. 1964 (Box 8)
  - Scientific Method, 1967 (Box 8)
  - The Scientific Revolution. (Box 8)
  - Sense and Nonsense -- A Modern Critique of Language. (Box 8)
  - The Social Import of Automatic Control. (Box 8)
  - The Social Sciences. (Box 8)
  - The Sociology of Knowledge and Philosophy of Science. (Box 8)
  - Some Current Issues. Introduction. (Box 8)
  - Some Issues in Teilhard's Theory of Cosmogenesis. (Box 8)
  - Some Leading Principles of Dewey's Logical Theory. (Box 8)
  - Some Notes on Determinism. (Box 8)
  - Some Reflections on Myth and Symbols in Science. (Box 8)
  - Some Reflections on the Use of Language in the Natural Sciences. (Box 8)
  - Some Theses in the Philosophy of Logic. (Box 8)
  - Sovereign Reason. Preliminary Introduction. (Box 8)
  - Sovereign Reason. (1) - (3) (Box 8)
  - State University Centennial Symposium., ( Speech.) (Box 8)
  - The Structure of Evolutionary Explanations. (Box 8)
  - The Structure of Science., ( 1st Draft. (1) - (6); 2nd Draft (1) - (3) (Box 9)
  - The Structure of Science., ( 2nd Draft (4) - (8); 3rd Draft (1) - (8) (Box 10)
  - The Structure of Science., ( Publisher's Copy. (1) - (11) (Box 11)
  - The Structure of Science., ( Corrected Galleys.) (Box 12)
  - The Supremacy of Method (Box 13)
  - Teleology Revisited. (1) - (4) (Box 13)
  - Theory and Observation (Box 13)
  - Truth and Certainty in Science (Box 13)
  - Types of Causal Explanations in Science (Box 13)
  - The Universe and the Paradox of Relevance (Box 13)
  - Verifiability, Truth, Verification (Box 13)
  - What Do Communists Understand by Marxism-Leninism? (Box 13)
  - Wittgenstein (Box 13)
  - Unidentified Mss. (1) - (2) (Box 13)
  - Unidentified Mss. (3) - (4) (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous Introductions (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous Book Reviews (1) - (10) (Box 14)
- Series IV: Speeches and Lectures
  - On index cards (Box 15)
- Series V: Notebooks
  - Algebra, ( vols) (Box 16)
  - Bolzano (Box 16)
  - Cornford, F. M. From Religion to Philosophy. (Box 16)
  - Logic 101-102, 1931-1932 (Box 16)
  - Logic 101-102, 1932-1933 (Box 16)
  - Logic 101-102, 1933-1934 (Box 16)
  - Mathematics, ( volumes) (Box 16)
  - Philosophy Review (Box 16)
  - Tarski, ( vols ) (Box 16)
  - Miscellaneous, ( spiral notebooks ) (Box 16)
- Series VI: Notes
  - Algebra (1) - (2) (Box 17)
  - [City College] (Box 17)
  - Civilization and Progress (Box 17)
  - Cohen and Natural Law (Box 17)
  - Concept Formation in the Social Sciences (Box 17)
  - Dewey: Types of Logical Theory (Box 17)
  - Ethics (Box 17)
  - [Geometry] (Box 17)
  - History and the Social Sciences (Box 17)
  - C. J. KEYSE, Modern Geometry (Box 17)
  - Logic (1) - (2) (Box 17)
  - The Logic of Economic Analysis (Box 17)
  - Mathematics (1) - (2) (Box 17)
  - N. P. MEAD, The World War & Division and Reunion. (Box 17)
  - [Organizations] (Box 17)
  - Probability (Box 17)
  - The Problems of Evolutionary Theory (Box 18)
  - Salmon's "Statistical Relevance" Model (Box 18)
  - Reichenbach, Hans. (Box 18)
  - Richardson, Lewis F. (Box 18)
  - Miscellaneous (1) - (3) (Box 18)
- Series VII: Teaching Materials
  - Anatomy of Biological Thought. (1) - (2) (Box 18)
  - Conceptions and Critiques of Reason. (Box 18)
  - Contemporary Philosophical Problems. (Box 18)
  - Explanatory Methods of Empirical Science. (Box 18)
  - Foundations of Modern Physical Science. (Box 18)
  - Hebrew University of Jerusalem. (Box 18)
  - History of Biology. (Box 18)
  - Hull, C. L. (Box 18)
  - Jurisprudence. (Box 18)
  - Legal Philosophy Seminar. 1959-1969; Spring 1962 (Box 18)
  - Legal Philosophy Seminar, Autumn 1962; 963; Fall 1965; Fall 1967; Autumn 1968; Fall 1970; Fall 1971; Fall 1972 (Box 19)
  - Legal Philosophy Seminar Related Materials. (Box 19)
  - Logic (1) - (4) (Box 19)
  - Logic (1) - (5), 1937-1938 (Box 19)
  - Logic, 1941-1950 (Box 19)
  - Logic, 1943 (Box 20)
  - Logic, 1951-1952 (Box 20)
  - Logic. Examinations. (Box 20)
  - Logic. Related Materials. (1) - (2) (Box 20)
  - Logic in Practice.(1) - (2) (Box 20)
  - Logic of Social Inquiry, 1953; 1954 (Box 20)
  - Related Materials. (Box 20)
  - Logic of Social Research, 1955; 1956; 1957; 1959; 1961; 1964 (Box 20)
  - Logic of Social research. Related Materials (Box 20)
  - Logical Theory (1) - (2), 1948-1949 (Box 21)
  - Logical Theory, 1952-1953. (Box 21)
  - Nineteenth Century Philosophies of Science (Box 21)
  - Philosophy Examinations. (1) - (3) (Box 21)
  - Philosophy of Civilization. (Box 21)
  - Philosophy of Language. (1) - (3) (Box 21)
  - Philosophy of Law, Spring 1963; Spring 1978. (Box 21)
  - Philosophy of Law. Examinations. (Box 21)
  - Philosophy of Law, ( Reading Lists.) (Box 22)
  - Philosophy of Law. Related Materials (1) - (6) (Box 22)
  - Philosophy of Mathematics. (1) - (5) (Box 22)
  - Philosophy of Mathematics. (6) - (10) (Box 23)
  - Philosophy of Mathematics (1) - (5), 1957 (Box 23)
  - Philosophy of Science. (Box 24)
  - Philosophy of Science, 1943.; 1950.; 1954.; 1958. (Box 24)
  - Philosophy of Science Seminar, 1961. (Box 24)
  - Philosophy of Science Seminar (1) - (2), 1968; 1971. (Box 24)
  - Philosophy of Science. Related Materials. (Box 24)
  - Probability and Induction. (1) - (6) (Box 24)
  - Reading Lists. (Box 25)
  - Science and Imagination. (Box 25)
  - Scientific Methods and Stages in Their Historical Development (Box 25)
  - Swarthmore College Honors, ( Examinations.) (Box 25)
  - Theory of Knowledge, 1951.; 1954. (Box 25)
  - Theory of Knowledge, 1955; 1956; 1966. (Box 25)
  - Related Materials. (1) - (3) (Box 25)
  - Theory of Meaning. (Box 25)
  - Theory of Value. [University Seminar] (Box 25)
  - The Thought of the Nineteenth Century. (1) - (3) (Box 25)
  - Turning Points in the History of Science. (Box 25)
  - University of Melbourne. (Box 25)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 25)
- Series VIII: Subject Files
  - Academy of Humanism. (Box 26)
  - Agriculture, Department of (Box 26)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences. (Box 26)
  - American Economic Association Conference. (Box 26)
  - American Friends of Hebrew University. (Box 26)
  - American Philosophical Society. (Box 26)
  - American Philosophical Society. Annual Meeting, 1964 (Box 26)
  - American University. Hurst Philosophy Lecture. (Box 26)
  - Bibliographic References. (Box 26)
  - The British Academy. (Box 26)
  - Carnap, Rudolf. (Box 26)
  - Carus Lectures. (Box 26)
  - Catholic University of America. (Box 26)
  - Columbia University Lectures, 1973 (Box 26)
  - Conference for Federal Science Executives. (Box 26)
  - Cooper Union. (Box 26)
  - Descartes Tricentenary. (Box 26)
  - John DEWEY Foundation. (1) - (3) (Box 26)
  - John DEWEY Foundation. Essay Project; Minutes. (Box 27)
  - Edel Festschrift. (Box 27)
  - Educational Policies Commission. (Box 27)
  - Einstein Centennial. (Box 27)
  - Einstein College Colloquium. (Box 27)
  - Encyclopedia of the Twentieth Century. (Box 27)
  - Fordham University Conference, 1965 (Box 27)
  - Philipp FRANK Dinner. (Box 27)
  - Freiss, Horace L. (Box 27)
  - Gšdel, Kurt. (Box 27)
  - Gšdel's Proof. (Box 27)
  - Harvard Commencement, 1966. (Box 27)
  - Haverford College Institute. (Box 27)
  - KQED Computer Series. (1) (Box 27)
  - KQED Computer Series. (2) (Box 28)
  - Journal of Philosophy Notes on Tadeuxz KOTARBINSKI Translation. (Box 28)
  - Paul F. LAZARSFELD Fund. (Box 28)
  - Logic of Historical Explanation. Conference. (1) - (2) (Box 28)
  - Logical Positivism. Conference. (Box 28)
  - Minnesota Center for the Philosophy of Science. (Box 28)
  - Morgenbesser Festschrift. (Box 28)
  - Nagel Speech Announcements. (Box 28)
  - National Academy of Sciences. National Research Council. (1) - (2) (Box 28)
  - National Academy of Sciences National Research Council. (3) (Box 29)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities. (Box 29)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities. Interdisciplinary Institute. (Box 29)
  - National Science Foundation. (Box 29)
  - New School for Social Research. (Box 29)
  - Charles PEIRCE Colloquium. (Box 29)
  - Charles PEIRCE Colloquium. Related Items. (Box 29)
  - Phi Delta Kappa Symposium on Educational Research. (Box 29)
  - Philosophy of Education Society. (Box 29)
  - Philosophy of Science Association (1) - (2) (Box 29)
  - Princeton University. (Box 29)
  - Randall, J. H. (Box 30)
  - Reichenbach, Hans. (Box 30)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Grant (Box 30)
  - Andrei SAKHAROV Conference, 1981 (Box 30)
  - Science, Philosophy and Religion Symposium, 1965 (Box 30)
  - Scientific Frontiers and their Interaction with Society. (Box 30)
  - Smith College. Science Committee. (Box 30)
  - Solow, Herbert. (Box 30)
  - Sterling Forest Conference Program. (Box 30)
  - The Tamiment Institute (1) - (2) (Box 30)
  - Teleology Revisited. (Box 30)
  - University Center in Virginia (Box 30)
  - University of Chicago. Conceptual Foundations of Science. (Box 30)
  - Venuxem Lectures. (Box 30)
  - Miscellaneous. (Box 30)
  - Clippings. (Box 30)
- Series IX: Manuscripts inscribed to E. Nagel
  - A - M (Box 31)
  - S - W (Box 32)
- Series X: Printed Materials
  - Printed Books inscribed to Nagel (Box 33 - 35)
  - Printed Materials and Printed Books by Nagel (Box 36)
- Series XI: 1989 Addition
  - Subseries XI.1: Introduction to Logic and Scientific Method
    - Variant Draft-ver. 1, ( a.m.s. (1) (Box 37)
    - Variant Draft-ver. 2, ( t.m.s.(2) (Box 37)
    - Variant Draft-ver. 2, exercises and analytic, ( index t.m.s. (carbon) (3) (Box 37)
    - Variant Draft-ver. 2, carbon, ( t.m.s. (carbon) (4) (Box 37)
  - Subseries XI.2: Notes
    - Miscellaneous (Box 37)
  - Subseries XI.3: Teaching Materials
    - Grade Book for Philosophy Courses (Box 37)